Danny Collinson

dannycollinson12@gmail.com | 610-290-3410 | West Chester, PA, USA linkedin.com/in/danny-collinson | github.com/dannycollinson | dannycollinson.com

Summary

Data Scientist and recent Caltech graduate with five years of experience building data and machine learning projects in academic and industry settings. Built pipelines for processing and analysis of large datasets in biological, geospatial, and astrophysics applications; implemented machine learning algorithms and state-of-the-art vision and language models using common machine learning frameworks; and developed statistical models to extract insights from large datasets. With a diverse set of experiences and a deep skill set combined with unparalleled determination, I am a valuable asset to any team.

Education

California Institute of Technology

September 2019 - June 2024

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computation and Neural Systems

Pasadena, CA

• GPA: 4.0/4.0

Relevant Coursework: Large Language and Vision Models, Data Analysis and Statistical Inference, Relational Databases,
LLMs as Agents, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Data Mining, Computational Biology and Bioinformatics

Work Experience

Data Science Intern

June 2023 - September 2023

Recursion Pharmaceuticals

Salt Lake City, UT

- Developed 2 new statistical metrics for analysis of large experimental datasets that were used to improve model performance
- Implemented advanced machine learning techniques in PyTorch to improve data processing efficiency and reduce costs
- Deployed monitoring tools to the data science and QA teams in collaboration with a 20-person cross-functional team, ensuring data integrity for downstream processing and models

Computational Biology Researcher

May 2022 - September 2022

Parker Lab at Caltech

Pasadena, CA

- Built data pipeline leveraging deep learning and statistical modeling to accelerate image processing speed by a factor of 100
- Automated microscopy analysis and increased measurement accuracy by an estimated 10% for an upcoming publication

Computational Astrophysics Researcher

May 2020 - January 2021

Harrison Lab at Caltech

Pasadena, CA

- Implemented statistical analysis methods using common data science tools including Python, NumPy, pandas, SciPy, and Jupyter notebooks on HPC clusters to perform source classification and deliver insights from large datasets
- Initiated development of an end-to-end data pipeline for automated data processing and classification, improving processing speed and efficiency in handling large datasets and decision-making

Teaching Assistant

September 2023 - December 2023

Professor Justin Bois at Caltech

Pasadena, CA

• Instructed 85 students in the graduate-level course Introduction to Data Analysis in the Biological Sciences, developing their skills in statistical modeling, numerical optimization, data visualization, and exploratory data analysis in Python

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, PyTorch, NumPy, pandas, scikit-learn, Jupyter, Matplotlib, SciPy, Bokeh, seaborn Tools: SQL, git, GitHub, cloud computing (AWS, GCP, HPC), Docker, Bash, shell, Linux, MCMC, APIs, PostgreSQL Topics: deep learning, large datasets, statistics, computer vision, LLMs, Bayesian stats, prompt engineering, exploratory analysis

Projects

Temperature Prediction from GIS Spectra

September 2023 - December 2023

- Led team of 3 in ML project to predict surface temperatures from spectral data, achieving error of less than 1 C
- · Created a new ML dataset from raw NASA data in collaboration with JPL scientists to study of novel research questions
- Built model training and testing frameworks and designed CNN-based model architectures alongside Professor Katie Bouman for use with autoencoder-generated embeddings to deliver accurate predictions

CheXpert Machine Learning Competition

April 2023 - June 2023

- · Orchestrated training of multi-GPU PyTorch models on HPC clusters using Slurm Bash scripts to enable powerful classifiers
- Developed a pipeline to process over 224k chest x-rays, adding augmentations to further improve model diagnosis accuracy
- Placed 3rd as a solo contestant competing against teams of 5 in Caltech's annual machine learning competition